该死  谢尔比又胖了
Damn! Shelby put on some weight.
他喜欢喝好酒
He loved a good pint, he did.
我觉得不好的也喜欢
Bad one too, it feels like.
你真蠢  华莱士
You're daft, Wallace.
如果你不信我  就去查查吧
Look it up if you don't believe me.
我是绿宝石岛[爱尔兰岛]之子
I'm a son of the Emerald Isle.
我知道《万花迎春》的歌词
I know the lyrics to Me Wild Irish Rose,
并不是"你可以找每一根头发
and they're not, "You may search every hair,
但没什么能相提并论"
but none shall compare..."
而是"你可以到处寻找..."
They're, "You may search everywhere--"
早上好  博汉南先生
Top o' the morning, Mr. Bohannon.
快
Come on.
我们还以为你死了  先生
We thought you was for the muck wagon, sir.
还没  先生们
Not yet, gentlemen.
还没呢
Not yet.
你没回家时我还担心你呢
I was worried about you when you didn't come home.
我去见牧师了
I went to see the church lady.
别担心
Don't worry.
不是她干的
Wasn't her that done this.
你可以等到上午的
Could have waited until the morning.
不  我必须这样做
No, needed doing.
我拜托她帮助你和威廉
Asked her to help you and William.
铁路公司可以让你休息一天
The railroad can spare you for a day.
如果我不工作  就没法照顾你和孩子了
Can't take care of you and the baby if I don't work.
至少让我给你弄点吃的
Let me at least go get you some food.
已经在浪费时间了
Day's already wasting.
博汉南  把这里当自己家吧
Oh, by all means, Bohannon, make yourself at home.
我看你在结交朋友啊
Making friends, I see.
你的小镇真友好
Real friendly town you got here.
怎么  出什么事了  博汉南先生
What? What's the matter, mr. Bohannon?
当地住民没为你粗犷的魅力倾倒吗
The local "Denizenry" not taken with your rough charm?
都没住民这个词儿
"Denizenry" ain't a word.
-有的  -没有
- Yes, it is. - No, it ain't.
有的  总之  我可以派人逮捕你
Yes-- anyway, I can have you arrested
罪名是偷窃政府财产
for stealing government property.
亨廷顿已经打通...
Huntington's already through--
打通了内华达山脉
through the Sierras.
你的总工程师差点害死自己
Your chief engineer almost got hisself killed
来证明他没法炸穿页岩山
proving he can't blast through a shale mountain.
你得用别的方法
You need to try something else.
没有别的方法了
There is nothing else.
我的测量员找不到可通过顶峰的路线
My surveyors could not find a passable route over the peak.
我会再看看的
Figured I'd give her another look.
你的工作在外面  博汉南
Your job, out on the grade, Bohannon.
今天不是
Not today.
拿着这个罗盘
Take this compass.
我的总工程师打破了那个
My chief engineer broke that one.
那人该被炒掉
That man should be fired.
他救了你的命
He saved your life.
他不听指挥  十分鲁莽
He is insubordinate and reckless.
他也许能挽回被你毁了的隧道
He may well save the hash you've made out of the tunnel.
凿隧道是你的主意
The tunnel was your idea.
我完全是照你的吩咐做的
I have done exactly as you ordered.
你没帮我通过谢尔曼峰
You have not gotten me through Sherman Peak!
博汉南要留下来
Bohannon stays.
我听说史密斯保卫站包庇了那些在镇上
I heard Fort Smith is harboring them Mormons
乱放枪的摩门教徒
who shot up town.
没什么能阻止他们
Ain't nothing stopping 'em
策马前行  再次袭击
from saddling up and doing it again.
一个摩门教徒为什么会在小镇上安家
Why would a Mormon make this town home?
她的同类都不在这里
None of her people are here.
她嫁给了卡伦·博汉南
She's married to Cullen Bohannon.
他也是摩门教徒吗
He's Mormon too?
他是铁道筑路工人
He's a railroad man.
他跟一个小女孩结婚了
Who took a child bride.
他们没法明辨是非
They don't know right from wrong
因为他们不信《圣经》
because they don't believe in the Bible.
是的  摩门教是暴力的邪教
It's true. Mormons are a violent cult.
如果他们不寻求救赎
If they don't seek redemption,
就必定被地狱里的烈火焚烧
nothing will save them from the fires of hell.
我需要一些煤油
I need some kerosene...
还有火柴
and matches too.
摩门教徒相信《圣经》
Mormons do believe in the Bible.
我们也遵循耶稣的教诲
And we also follow the teachings of Jesus Christ,
特别是友善待人的教诲
particularly when it comes to kindness to others.
迈克尔·麦克吉尼斯
Michael McGinnes?
有人来了
There we go.
你们都知道我是谁
Y'all know very well who I am.
-我要关闭你的赌场  -凭什么
- I'm closing your casino. - On what grounds?
美国政府已将此建筑没收充公
This building is condemned by order of the U.S. government.
清场
Clear it out!
-给我走  -干什么
- On your feet! - Hey!
-过来  你个婊子  -把你的脏手拿开
- Come on, you whore. - Get your damn hands off of me!
你给我放开那位女士
You, unhand that lady!
给我滚
Get out!
过来
Come on!
快滚
Move it along!
走吧  爱尔兰傻子
Let's go, you dumb mick.
行了  米奇
That's enough, Mickey!
竟敢来关我的场子
Shut down my bar, will you?
起来  给我起来
Get up. Get up!
不要反抗  米奇  我会把你救出来的
Don't resist, Mickey. I'll get you out.
听到没有  这里杜兰特说了算  不是你们
Hear that? Durant runs this town, not you lot.
他明天之前肯定会把我救出来的
He'll have me out before the end of the day.
我相信民兵没有虐待你吧
I trust the militia is treating you fairly.
是的
Oh. Well, yes.
拘禁让我有机会去...
My internment has given me the opportunity for...
深切地祈祷和反思
deep prayer and reflection.
我一直在为
I have been praying
我的敌人祈祷
for mine enemies,
正如耶稣受难前
as Jesus did during his incarceration
被监禁时一样
before crucifixion.
达森主教  别这样
Bishop Dutson, please.
他不是主教
He is not a bishop.
我们都听到他的忏悔了
We all heard his confession.
你们
What...
到底
exactly...
听到了什么
did you hear?
你说你把真正的达森主教淹死了
You said you drowned the real bishop Dutson.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
教区记录员记下类似的话了吗
Did the ward clerk take any such notes?
-没有  -这样啊
- No. - Oh.
但是我听到了
But I heard you.
你听到的是圣灵
You heard the holy spirit
通过你们的主教说话
speaking through your bishop,
是在净化谋杀你儿子的
cleansing the soul of the man
凶手的灵魂
who murdered your son.
不是这样的
That's not true.
不要担心  海彻兄弟
No, be not afraid, Brother Hatch.
那天你目睹的是一件神圣之事
You witnessed a spiritual event that day.
预知  启示
Visions, revelations,
见证一切
sublime to witness,
却难以领悟
yet difficult to discern.
他在歪曲事实
He's twisting what happened.
他有说话的权利
He has a right to speak.
你提议我们绞死他
You have proposed that we hang him
罪名是冒充主教
for impersonating a bishop.
天父需要确信无疑
Heavenly father demands there be no doubt.
赞美上帝
Praise God.
我已经发电报给摩门教会了
I telegraphed the Mormon church,
真正的主教就是从那来的
from which the real bishop joined us.
教区的领袖芬奇主教
A reply is coming from Bishop Finch,
马上就会答复
the head of the ward,
会证明这个人...
that will prove this man...
需要正义
needs justice.
确实  希望正义得以伸张
Indeed, and may justice be done.
赞美上帝
Praise God.
吁
Whoa.
来
Come on.
顶级哈瓦那雪茄  我的私人珍藏
Havana's finest, from my private stock.
你我二人  我们都是
You and I-- we are both men
经验丰富  知晓自己优势之人
with experience enough to know when we have the upper hand.
同意
Agreed.
所以我得说...
So let me say...
我钦佩你关闭赌场的大胆行径
I admire your bold act in closing the casino.
这显示出了你的力量
It showed strength.
那块地是做我新联邦办公室的绝佳地点
And that site is perfect for my new federal offices.
坎贝尔广场已经在着手设计了
The designs for Campbell Plaza are under way.
我明白  坎贝尔先生
You've made your point, Mr. Campbell.
但是我们需要强壮的人来建造铁路
But we need hard men to build the railroad.
根据我的经验  他们闲着的时候
And in my experience, they are never more dangerous
最为危险了
than when they are idle.
麦克吉尼斯先生已经证明自己擅长提供
Now, Mr. Mcginnes has proven himself adept at offering
合适的娱乐来帮我们管理那些人
the right amusements to help manage the men.
对
Yes.
希望您能宽宏大量
You are in a position to be magnanimous.
可他袭击了联邦法警
Well, he assaulted a federal marshal.
他那是一时冲动
A rash act in the heat of the moment.
在一些州凭他的行为可以执行枪决
He'd be shot for that offense in some states.
那还好怀俄明州
Well, let's be grateful Wyoming
还没有独立司法权
has not yet achieved statehood.
市长不能放
The Mayor stays in jail.
谢谢你送来的雪茄
Thank you for the cigars.
有人吗
Hello?
博汉南夫人
Mrs. Bohannon.
我是露丝·科尔
I'm Ruth Cole.
-教会的那位女士  -是的
- The church lady. - Yes.
我想为我今早的行为道歉
I wanted to apologize for my behavior this morning.
那样是不对的
It was unkind.
我希望你能原谅我
I hope you can forgive me.
教区的一些女信徒捐赠了这些
Several women in the parish donated these.
你明天可以来教堂见她们
You could meet them at church tomorrow.
-我知道你不是位信徒  -我是
- I know you're not a believer-- - But I am...
我信奉天父和他的先知
In the heavenly father and his true prophet,
约瑟夫·史密斯
Joseph Smith.
我要承认  我对摩门教不是很熟悉
I'll admit, I'm not well versed in Mormonism.
也许你可以帮我理解为什么约瑟夫·史密斯
Perhaps you could help me understand why Joseph Smith
提倡一夫多妻制  比方说
advocated polygamy, for instance.
多偶制是上帝的旨意
Plural marriage is god's will.
-上帝的旨意  -是的
- God's will? - Yes.
主命令我们多生育  多结合
The lord commands us to be fruitful and multiply
来建立摩门教教徒的王国
so that we can build the kingdom of the Latter-Day Saints.
但是那个王国是建立在
But that kingdom is predicated
对女性的剥削之上的
on the exploitation of women,
强迫她们去分享丈夫
forcing them to share husbands,
拒绝她们去做牧师
refusing to allow them to be ordained as clergy.
你必须要看到里面的不公平
You-- you must see the injustice in that.
我看的清清楚楚
I see clarity in it.
我知道我的归属
I know who I'm meant to be...
相夫教子的家庭主妇
a woman whose place is in the home
就是我的角色
looking after her children.
礼拜十点开始
The service is at 10:00.
那么
So...
你觉得杜兰特先生
about what time do you expect Mr. Durant
什么时间会来这里放了你
to swoop in here and free you?
他是你的搭档  对吧
He is your partner, right...
这里管事的是吧
The one who runs things around here?
我了解他这种人
Yeah, I know men like him...
大人物  跟你交朋友...
big men. Keep you close--
闭嘴  给我拿杯水
Quit your yapping and get me a cup of water.
没问题  镇长先生
Sure thing, Mr. Mayor.
这应该够你喝到杜兰特先生来了
That should hold you till Mr. Durant gets here.
华莱士
Wallace?
那不是个点篝火的好地方
It's a bad spot for a campfire.
政府没收了赌场
Government took the casino.
米奇在监狱
Mickey's in jail.
看来他不同意业主变更啊
I take it he didn't agree with the change in ownership.
我来见朋友而已
Just here to see my friend.
我觉得我们扯平了
I figured you and me are square.
你来这是比伤口  还是带我出去的
You come here to compare bruises or bust me out?
后者我说了不算
The latter ain't up to me no more.
是啊
Yeah.
杜兰特先生在想办法释放我  所以...
Mr. Durant's working on my release, so...
我可不会去指望这个
Wouldn't count on that.
杜兰特只做对自己最有利的事
Durant does what's best for Durant.
所以山北的四十英亩荒地
That's how I ended up with 40 acres
才会在我手里
of worthless land in the north valley.
见鬼  小子
Shit, son.
靠近点
Come here.
当我遇见你的时候
When I met you...
你只有些廉价的彩绘玻璃
you didn't have nothing but some cheap painted glass
和家乡的故事
and stories of home.
然后你把它们变成了妓院和赌场
And you turned that into a whorehouse and a casino.
你可以再来一次的
You can do that again.
让杜兰特见鬼去吧
Hell with Durant.
没有他  我根本没影响力
Without him, I got no leverage.
那正是肖恩所认为的
That is exactly what Sean thought.
别让我也埋了你
Don't leave me to bury you similar.
好吗
Okay?
登车结束
All aboard!
是的  先生  你好
Yes, sir. How y'all doing?
米奇  在等着你把他弄出去呢
Mickey's, uh, expecting you to get him sprung.
米奇需要学习控制他的脾气
Mickey needs to learn to curb his temper
如果他想主持生意的话
if he wants to run a business.
听我说
Let me tell you something...
赌场只是坎贝尔下手的开始
Casino's just the start of what Campbell's fixing to take.
很快他就会大举进攻的
Pretty soon he'll come for it all.
坎贝尔只是位官僚  不足为惧
Campbell is a bureaucrat, nothing more.
他是投机家
He's a carpetbagger.
他们在南部做的第一件事就是重修铁路
First thing they did in the south, rebuild the railroads.
现在  他还有左膀右臂在帮他
Now, odds are, he's got friends helped him do that,
大家都等不及再来一次了
men just itching to do it again.
他明白里面有利有权可图
Now, he knows that there's money in it and power.
没有投机家能抢走我的铁路
No carpetbagger will take my railroad.
好吧
Yeah.
在密西西比时我也是这么想我农场的
That's what I thought about a farm back in Mississippi.
你搞定谢尔曼峰了吗
Have you conquered Sherman Peak yet?
正在努力
Working on it.
继续修我的铁路  博汉南先生
Get my railroad moving, Mr. Bohannon.
我想让你明天坐前面
I'd like you to sit in front tomorrow.
而且尽量不要拉扯衬衫衣领
And try not to tug at your shirt collar.
我不想下地狱
I don't want to go to hell.
几个月的沉默后  这就是你想说的吗
Months of silence, and that's what you have to say?
上帝应该不会这样对你的
I doubt that's God's plan for you.
你有时候很淘气  但是
You're naughty sometimes, but that--
我是摩门教徒
I'm Mormon.
你的族人都去哪了
Where are your people?
没事了
It's all right.
不想说就不说了
We don't have to talk about this.
现在你很安全
You're safe.
-杜兰特先生  -伊娃
- Mr. Durant - Ah, Eva.
记得去年你给我的股票吗
You know that stock you gave me last year?
值多少钱
How much is it worth?
现在几乎一文不值
Virtually nothing at the moment.
我应该继续去当妓女
I should go back to whoring.
如果你需要钱  我可以帮你
If it's money you need, let me help.
杜兰特先生  我不能接受你的施舍
Mr. Durant, I can't take no charity from you.
就算是我借给你的
Think of it as a loan.
不  我不能拿
No, I can't.
教堂那位姑娘来过了
Church lady stopped by.
是吗  然后呢...抱歉  你说什么
Yeah, and-- I'm sorry. What?
教堂那位姑娘
The church lady.
她邀请我们明天去参加礼拜
She invited us to services tomorrow.
而你
And, uh...
你不想去吗
You don't want to go?
她不喜欢摩门教徒
She doesn't like Mormons.
在你之前她没见过多少摩门教徒  但是
I doubt she's met many before you, but, uh...
露丝虽然心直口快  但她是个好人
Ruth speaks her mind, but she's a good woman,
而且她可以帮你融入这里
and she can help you make your way here.
那是我丈夫应该做的事
That's my husband's job.
我在养你和威廉啊
I'm providing for you and William.
我父亲供养他所有的妻子和孩子
Father provided for all of his wives and his children,
但他还和我们一起吃饭
but he still ate with us,
一起做礼拜
worshipped with us.
就像你和你第一个妻子那样...
Much like the life that you had with your first wife...
但你抛下了那一切
But you left all of that behind.
那时在打仗
There was a war.
战争已经结束了
War's over.
回屋去
Get back inside.
去吧
Go on.
娶了我之后你没有做错什么
You know, you--you did right by me with this marriage.
我很感激  真的
I'm grateful. I am.
我猜
I guess...
我应该懂得你不是那种居家男人
I should have known that family life wasn't for you.
从坎贝尔在亚特兰大一起工作过的人开始吧
Start with the people Campbell worked with in Atlanta.
看看有没有谁是铁路上的
See if any of them were railroad men.
看看他在战后
Oh, and find out what involvement he had
铁路重建方面都参与过什么
in the reconstruction of the railroads after the war.
你知道我有工程师学位吧
You do know I have an engineering degree.
那你就应该够聪明
Then you should have the intelligence
有能力发几份电报
to be able to send a few telegrams.
就这样吧  德莱尼
That will be all, Delaney.
伊娃
Ah, Eva!
你又来了
You came around.
我接受你的钱  杜兰特先生
I'll take your money, Mr. Durant...
你干我吧
for a poke.
不  你误会了
No, you misunderstand!
我给你钱不是那个意思
No, I--that was not a condition of my offer.
我知道现在自己不怎么漂亮
Look, I know I ain't so pretty right now,
但我打扮得还不错
but I clean up good.
不
No!
伊娃  你很漂亮
Eva, you're beautiful.
那为什么不来上上我
Well, then why not take a ride?
又不麻烦
It's no trouble.
反正我也无所谓了
Don't mean nothing to me no mores, anyway.
那样的话  亲爱的  就太可悲了
That, my dear, is a tragedy.
我喜欢你
I like you.
我也知道你喜欢我
And I know you like me.
所以
So?
来吧
Come on.
我给你个好价钱
I'll give you a good price.
听着
Listen to me.
我的钱你拿去
You will take my money.
我的东西你也吃一些
You are going to eat my food.
然后你去洗个澡
And then you are going to get into my bath,
因为说实话  你开始有点
because, truth be told, you are beginning to smell
发臭了
a little ripe.
我
I...
我不能那么做
I can't.
你可以  快去吧
You can, and you will.
你是这里为数不多的  我喜欢的人之一
You are one of the few people I like around here.
所以我要为你做这些
I'll pay you for that.
洗得还好吗
You all right in there?
是的
Yep.
如果愿意你可以进来
You can come in, if you like.
不用了
No, I-I'm fine.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
我想不通
Don't make no sense.
因为我们是朋友
Because we're friends.
除了客人  我从来没有过朋友
I ain't never had no friends weren't customers.
那是他们的损失
Their loss.
-我能问你个问题吗  -当然
- Can I ask you a question? - Of course.
你觉得天下女人皆娼妓吗
Do you think all women are whores?
你为什么要这么说
Why would you say that?
上次我洗澡的时候
Last time I was in a bath,
一个男人就是这么告诉我的
a man made clear that opinion.
我觉得女人是上天恩赐的至宝
I consider women to be God's most glorious creatures.
而我有幸爱上了其中一位
I was fortunate enough to love one.
你的妻子吗
Your wife?
不
No.
曾经可能爱过她
At one time, maybe.
但自从我们的儿子死后  我们...
But after our boy died, we...
我们最多只能算是生意伙伴了
Well, we were business partners at best.
我坐牢那段时间里
When I was in jail,
身无分文
penniless,
她就离开了我
she left me.
那是她的损失
Her loss.
谢谢
Thank you.
不要停止你的爱
Don't make the love stop.
现在情况有好转吗
Does it get any easier?
没有
No.
事实上  一点都没有
Indeed, no, it does not.
你一晚上都没上床
You didn't come to bed.
我得干活啊
Well, I had work to do,
而且我觉得你也不想让我待在床上
and I figured you didn't want me there.
我当然想啊
Of course I do.
我除了铁路以外还拥有了家庭
It's been a long time since I had a family
上次有这种感觉还是很久之前的事了
other than the railroad.
所以我想着今天早上我们可以一起去教堂
So I figured we could go to church this morning...
如果你愿意的话
together, if you're willing.
我非常乐意
I'd like that.
去做礼拜之前我还得先处理些事  好吗
I got to take care of something before service, all right?
*奔跑吧  亨利  奔跑吧*
*Run, Henry, run, yeah*
*奔跑吧  内森  奔跑吧*
*Run, Nathan, run, oh*
*奔跑吧  勒罗伊  奔跑吧*
*Run, Leroy, run, I tell ya*
*你有权立于生命树之上*
*You got a right to the tree of life*
*上帝之子皆有权*
*All god's children got a right*
*你有权立于生命树之上*
*You got a right to the tree of life*
*亲爱的孩子  你有权*
*Oh, children, you got a right*
*你有权立于生命树之上*
*You got a right to the tree of life*
*希伯来子民亦有权*
*Hebrew children got a right*
*你有权立于生命树之上*
*You got a right to the tree of life*
*让我来告诉你  你有权*
*I've come to tell you, you got a right*
*你有权立于生命树之上*
*You got a right to the tree of life*
*奔跑吧  博汉南  奔跑吧*
*Run, Bohannon, run, I say*
*你有权立于生命树之上*
*You got a right to the tree of life*
*奔跑吧  博汉南  让我告诉你*
*Run, Bohannon, run, I tell ya*
*你有权立于生命树之上*
*You got a right to the tree of life*
*上帝之子皆有权*
*All God's children got a right*
*你有权立于生命树之上*
*You got a right to the tree of life*
阿门  好样的
Amen. All right.
-帕萨姆  -早上好
- Psalms. - How you doing this morning?
早上好
Morning.
问你个事
So let me ask you something.
今天召集一队工人要多少钱
How much to get a crew together today?
你有多少钱
How much you got?
不够
No.
这点钱都召不到十个人
Can't get more than ten men for that,
而且最多干两小时
two hours, most.
行吧  做完礼拜在山下等我
All right, meet you at the grade after church.
大家伙儿们都盼着下午的棒球赛呢
Oh, boys been hankering for a game of baseball this afternoon.
你想召人就得趁现在
You want a crew, got to go now.
行  现在选人吧
All right, pick the crew.
伙计们
Fellas...
我知道今天是安息日  但是我们来活了
I know it's the lord's day, but we're gonna work.
杜兰特昨天来见我
Durant came by to see me yesterday.
他想让我把你放了
He asked for your release.
我拒绝了他
I told him no.
我有个提议  可以今天就还你自由
I have a proposition that could free you today.
你签了这份文件  把赌场转交给我就行了
Sign this paper giving me title to the casino.
我还是会雇你打理那里
I'll pay you to manage the place.
当然了  我也可以直接把你的财产偷走
Granted, I could just steal the property from you.
你早就这么干了
You already have.
我还是喜欢按法律办事
I prefer to do things legally.
200美元买下所有权
$200 for the title...
包括付你的工钱
salary for you.
杰瑟普会每周来收税
Jessup will pick up the tax every week.
把你的臭钱收起来
Shove your money up your arse.
别这样  麦克吉尼斯先生
Come now, Mr. Mcginnes.
你是个聪明人
You're a smart man.
没错  也是个注定会成功的人
Aye. And a comer too.
我两手空空地来到这个国家
I came to this country with nothing,
为自己打出了一片天下
and I built me a fortune.
我会东山再起的
I'll do it again...
我压根没义务讨你欢心
Beholden not to the likes of you
或者讨托马斯·杜兰特欢心
or to Thomas C. Durant.
我们绝对没法把这座山炸通
We damn sure can't blast through this mountain.
杜兰特也放弃了绕路的法子
Durant's given up on going around.
已经无计可施了
Got no choice but over.
那顿暴打是不是还把你脑子打糊涂了
That beating you took done scrambled your brain.
测量员看遍了整座山
Surveyors done been all over this mountain,
没找到一处平缓的地方
ain't found nowhere that wasn't too steep.
是  我看了记录
Yeah, I looked at the notes.
当时地上的积雪有六英尺
There was 6 foot of snow on the ground when they was out here.
我昨天在山顶  发现一个或许可行的办法
Now, I was up top yesterday, saw a way might work.
"或许"吗
"Might"?
如果我们能沿着山的边缘
If we carve a ledge the width of a train track
凿出铺设铁轨的路
on the mountain's outer edge.
你看
All right, look...
-看到那边的悬崖了吗  -看到了
- See that cliff over yonder? - Yeah.
我们在那凿出两度的斜坡
We gonna dig a 2% grade straight for it.
等我知道两小时我们能凿多远
When I know how far we can get in two hours,
就能算出全体工人需要多久能到山顶
I can figure how long it'll take a full crew to reach the summit.
杜兰特没让我们这么做
Could be Durant ain't have us try this
因为他知道不可能
'cause he know it's crazy.
只有一个办法能知道了
Well, only one way to find out.
来了吗
Did it come?
这是芬奇主教发来的
This is from Bishop Finch.
这上面说达森主教身高五尺六寸
It says Bishop Dutson is 5 feet, 6 inches tall,
棕色头发
brown hair,
身材健壮
portly girth.
站起来
Stand up.
你不是这封电报里说的人
You are not the man described in this telegram.
不
No.
你欺骗了我们整个族群
You have deceived this entire community.
告诉我你是谁
Tell me who you are!
我是
I am...
约瑟夫·达森主教
Bishop Joseph Dutson,
我从没见过芬奇主教
and I have never met Bishop Finch.
你们共事过三年
You prayed beside him for three years.
这个证明
This proves
你欺骗了我们所有人
that you have borne false witness to us all.
这只能证明发报人撒谎
It proves only that the author has lied
以印证你的幻觉
to support your delusion.
或者你就是发报人
Or perhaps you are the author,
海彻兄弟
Brother Hatch.
我要把这个送去长老会
I am bringing this to the Elders.
他们会判你有罪
They will find you guilty
送你上绞架的
and set you to the noose.
你确定他们有权吊死主教吗
Are you sure they have the authority to hang a bishop?
因为如果他们无权  你又错了
Because if they do not and you are wrong,
那被吊死的会是你  海彻兄弟
then you will hang, Brother Hatch,
还有长老们
as will the Elders.
如果长老会无权  那谁有
Who has the authority, if not the Elders?
一位无可指责的人
An unimpeachable man...
上帝的雄狮
the lion of the lord...
我们的兄弟  杨百翰
our brother Brigham Young.
请他来
Bring him here.
我会听从他的审判
I will abide by his judgment.
我们用的工具不对
These tools all wrong.
没用的
This ain't gonna work.
感谢各位祝我献身
Thank you for helping me consecrate
这座美丽的圣殿
this fine house of worship.
兄弟姐妹们
Brothers and sisters,
耶稣在世
Jesus Christ is alive
并显身于此
and present in this building.
如果我们不接受他做自己的上帝与救世主
And if we do not accept him as our personal lord and savior,
我们会焚身地狱
we will burn in hell.
阿门
Amen.
我说的只是有罪之人
I speak not of the innocents among us.
上帝说过
The Lord said,
"让小孩到我这里来
"Suffer the children to come unto me.
天堂是属于他们之地"
The kingdom of heaven belongs to such as these."
是那些背叛上帝
No, it is those who turn away
破坏教义的人
from the teachings of the lord
堕入地狱不得翻身
who will spend eternity in the fiery lake.
上帝要求我们敬爱神明
For he commands us to love our god,
也敬爱自己的邻居
as well as our neighbor.
你们敬爱神明吗
Do you love your god?
是
Yes.
敬爱邻居吗
Do you love your neighbor?
是
Yes.
我这周没有敬爱自己的邻居
I did not love my neighbor this week.
与同伴妄下论断
I sat in judgment on my fellow man.
我被自己的
I reveled in the pit
伪善所蒙蔽
of my own self-righteousness.
我理应被逐入黑暗
So I deserve to be cast out into darkness,
不值得救赎
and I do not deserve salvation.
我们都是
None of us does.
只有耶稣的怜恤能拯救我们
Only the blessed mercy of Jesus Christ can save us.
你好啊  小家伙
Hey, little man.
我去了教堂
I went to church.
-娜奥米...  -我知道
- Naomi... - I know.
我不会再问了
I'll stop asking.